<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: book | Jiajun Yao]]></title>
  <link href="http://blog.jjyao.me/blog/categories/book/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://blog.jjyao.me/"/>
  <updated>2025-08-22T23:05:17-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://blog.jjyao.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[jjyao]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[High Output Management]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.jjyao.me/blog/2025/08/17/high-output-management/"/>
    <updated>2025-08-17T21:29:32-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.jjyao.me/blog/2025/08/17/high-output-management</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The output of a manager is the output of the organizational units under his or her supervision or influence. This book talks about how to increase the managerial output.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Managerial Leverage</h2>

<p>Managerial output = Output of organization = A1 * L1 + A2 * L2 + &hellip; where A is a managerial activity and L is the corresponding leverage. Manager activities include information-gathering, information-giving, decision-making, nudging, and being a role model. Leverage, by definition, is the measure of the output generated by any given managerial activity. Based on the formula, a manager can increase his output by:</p>

<ol>
<li>Increase the rate with which a manager performs his activities, speeding up his work.</li>
<li>Increasing the leverage associated with the various managerial activities.</li>
<li>Shifting the mix of a manager&rsquo;s activities from those with lower to those with higher leverage.</li>
</ol>


<p>The art of management lies in the capacity to select from the many activities of seemingly comparable significance the one or two or three that provide leverage well beyond the others and concentrate on them. This is how we should allocate our time —— the single most important resource that we allocate from one day to the next. Given time is a finite resource, and when we say &ldquo;yes&rdquo; to one thing we are inevitably saying &ldquo;no&rdquo; to another, we should be very selective about things we choose to do.</p>

<h2>Meetings —— The Medium of Managerial Work</h2>

<p>There are two kinds of meetings. The first is <strong>process-oriented</strong> meeting, knowledge is shared and information is exchanged. Such meetings take place on a regularly scheduled basis. The second is <strong>mission-oriented</strong> meeting, the purpose is to solve a specific problem and produce a decision. They are ad hoc affairs, not scheduled long in advance, because they usually can&rsquo;t be.</p>

<p>One-on-one is a process-oriented meeting. It should be regarded as the subordinate&rsquo;s meeting, with its agenda and tone set by him.</p>

<p>For a mission-oriented meeting, the purpose should be decided beforehand and it&rsquo;s the meeting chairman&rsquo;s job to make sure the meeting accomplishs the purpose for which it was called. Since the goal of this type of meetings is to make a decision, we should control the number of attendees. A decision-making meeting is hard to keep moving if more than six or seven people attend. Eight people should be the absolute cutoff. Decision-making is not a spectator sport, because onlookers get in the way of what needs to be done. Once the meeting is over, the chairman must nail down exactly what happened by sending out minutes that summarize the discussion that occurred, the decision made, and the actions to be taken. And it&rsquo;s very important that attendees get the minutes quickly, before they forget what happened. The minutes should also be as clear and as specific as possible, telling the reader what is to be done, who is to do it, and when.</p>

<h2>Decisions, Decisions</h2>

<p>An organization does not live by its members agreeing with one another at all times about everything. It lives instead by people committing to support the decisions and the moves of the business.</p>

<p><img src="/images/post/high-output-management/ideal-decision-making-process.png"></p>

<p>The ideal decision-making process involves three stages. The first stage should be <strong>free</strong> discussion, in which all points of view and all aspects of an issue are openly welcomed and debated. The greater the disagreement and controversy, the more important becomes the word free. The next stage is reaching a <strong>clear</strong> decision. Again, the greater the disagreement about the issue, the more important becomes the word clear. Finally, everyone involved must give the decision reached by the group <strong>full</strong> support.</p>

<p>The person makes the decision is the DRI and everyone else needs to <strong>disagree and commit</strong> once the decision is made. The DRI should have the confidence to make the decision especially when consensus is not reached and the self-confidence mostly comes from a gut-level realization that nobody has ever died from making a wrong business decision, or taking inappropriate action, or being overruled (most decisions are two-way doors).</p>

<p>We shouldn&rsquo;t enter the decision-making stage too early or wait too long. If we make the decision too early, we may miss some opinions. If we make the decision too late (aiming for the absolutely right decision), we are not moving fast enough. Often, it&rsquo;s better to try out a 60-point decision and iterate on it quickly based on feedbacks than trying to find a 100-point decision endlessly.</p>

<p>For decision-making, one of the manager&rsquo;s key tasks is to settle six important questions in advance:</p>

<ul>
<li>What decision needs to be made?</li>
<li>When does it have to be made?</li>
<li>Who will decide?</li>
<li>Who will need to be consulted prior to making the decision?</li>
<li>Who will ratify or veto the decision?</li>
<li>Who will need to be informed of the decision?</li>
</ul>


<h2>Planning: Today&rsquo;s Actions for Tomorrow&rsquo;s Output</h2>

<p>Planning is to answer the qeustion: What do I have to do today to solve —— or better, avoid —— tomorrow&rsquo;s problem? Today&rsquo;s gap represents a failure of planning sometime in the past.</p>

<p>MBO (management-by-objectives) is a planning process that can be applied to daily work. A successful MBO system needs only to answer two questions:</p>

<ul>
<li>Where do I want to go? (The answer provides the objective).</li>
<li>How will I pace myself to see if I am getting there? (The answer gives us milestones, or key results.)</li>
</ul>


<h2>The Sports Analogy</h2>

<p>The role of the manager is that of the coach. First, an ideal coach takes no personal credit for the success of his team, and because of that his players trust him. Second, he is tough on his team. By being critical, he tries to get the best performance his team members can provide. Third, a good coach was likely a good player himself at one time. And having played the game well, he also understands it well.</p>

<h2>Performance Appraisal: Manager as Judge and Jury</h2>

<p>Performance reviews is the single most important form of task-relevant feedback we as supervisors can provide. The goal is to improve the subordinate&rsquo;s performance instead of cleansing our system of all the truths we may have observed about the subordinate so less may very well be more (give one feedback and one area for improvement at a time).</p>

<p>It might be counterintuitive but we should spend more time trying to improve the performance of our stars. After all, these people account for a disproportionately large share of the work in any organization. Put another way, concentrating on the stars is a high-leverage activity: if they get better, the impact on group output is very great indeed. We must keep in mind, however, that no matter how stellar a person&rsquo;s performance level is, there is always room for improvement.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The 4 Disciplines of Execution]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.jjyao.me/blog/2023/04/16/the-4-disciplines-of-execution/"/>
    <updated>2023-04-16T21:21:10-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.jjyao.me/blog/2023/04/16/the-4-disciplines-of-execution</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This book shows how a team can execute an important goal successfully in the face of massive amount of day-to-day operations that are urgently required to keep the business running.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>There are lots of urgent things (whirlwind) to do every day to keep the lights on. Failure to do so can kill the business today. However, there are also important things to take the business to the next level. Failure to do those can kill the business tomorrow. As a result, being able to execute important things successfully while doing the day job is critical for the success of the business in the long term. To help teams to do so, this book presents a methodology called 4DX that consists of four disciplines.</p>

<h2>Discipline 1: Focus on the Wildly Important</h2>

<p>The key of the first discipline is <strong>focus</strong>. Attempting to spread the limited capacity across multiple goals is the most common cause of failure in execution. Instead, <strong>one and only one</strong> wildly important goal (WIG) should be identified and executed.</p>

<p>To identify the WIG, one can ask the following question: If every other aspect of our team&rsquo;s performance remained at its current level, what is the one area where significant improvement would have the greatest <strong>impact</strong>? The resulting WIG should be specific, clearly measurable and in the form of <strong>From X to Y by when</strong> (e.g. improve the NPS score from 1 to 6 by end of the year).</p>

<h2>Discipline 2: Act on the Lead Measures</h2>

<p>The key of the second discipline is <strong>leverage</strong>. Lag measures are the tracking measurements of the WIG and they tell you whether you achieve the WIG or not. For example, if the WIG is improving the NPS score from 1 to 6 by end of the year then the lag measure is the NP score. The issue with the lag measure is that you cannot influence it directly and it is lagging in the sense that by the time you get the result, it is already too late and the performance that drove it is in the past. In contrast, lead measures measure things that lead to the WIG and can be influenced by us directly. For example, burning 1000 calories every day is a good lead measure for a WIG of losing 20 pounds in 3 months.</p>

<p>Two basic characteristics of a valid lead measure are <strong>predictive</strong> and <strong>influenceable</strong>: it&rsquo;s predictive of achieving the WIG and can be influenced directly. There could be many lead measures for a WIG and finding the highest-leverage ones is perhaps the toughest and most intriguing challenge for leaders trying to execute a WIG. Finding lead measures requires the involvement of the frontline team members and that involvement brings engagement and commitment. In the end, it&rsquo;s the frontline team that acts on the lead measures. A leader can only veto but not dictate what the final lead measures should be. The resulting lead measures are the team&rsquo;s bet: they bet that by driving these lead measures, the team is going to achieve the WIG.</p>

<p><img src="/images/post/the-4-disciplines-of-execution/lead-measure.png"></p>

<h2>Discipline 3: Keep a Compelling Scoreboard</h2>

<p>The key of the third discipline is <strong>engagement</strong>. A compelling player&rsquo;s scoreboard that clearly shows whether a team is winning or losing drives the highest level of engagement and the engagement drives the highest level of performance. The fundamental purpose of a player&rsquo;s scoreboard is to motivate the players to win.</p>

<p>A compelling scoreboard has the following four characteristics:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>It&rsquo;s simple as a player&rsquo;s scoreboard in a sporting event, not a more complex coach&rsquo;s scoreboard.</p></li>
<li><p>It can be seen easily. A visible scoreboard makes sure that the WIG and lead measures are not forgotten in the constant urgency of day-to-day responsibilities.</p></li>
<li><p>It shows both the lead and lag measures. From the scoreboard, the team can see what they are doing (the lead measures) and what they are getting (the lag measures). Once the team sees that the lag measure is moving because of the efforts they have made on the leads, it has a dramatic effect on engagement because they know they are directly impacting the results.</p></li>
<li><p>It tells if a team is winning or losing immediately. If the team can&rsquo;t quickly determine if they are winning or not by looking at the scoreboard, then it&rsquo;s not a game, it&rsquo;s just data.</p></li>
</ul>


<h2>Discipline 4: Create a Cadence of Accountability</h2>

<p>The key of the fourth discipline is <strong>accountability</strong>. This is where execution actually happens. The previous three disciplines set up the game but until this discipline is applied, the team is not in the game. Without this discipline, there will always be actions the team members know they should perform but never actually do with real consistency due to whirlwind.</p>

<p>To create a cadence of accountability, a WIG session is held on the same day and at the same time every week with the following agenda:</p>

<ol>
<li><p>Account. Report on last week&rsquo;s commitments.</p></li>
<li><p>Review the scoreboard. Learn from successes and failures.</p></li>
<li><p>Plan. Clear the path and make new commitments.</p></li>
</ol>


<p>To figure out the <em>high-impact</em> commitments for the week, ask the question &ldquo;What are the one or two most important things I can do this week to impact the lead measures?&rdquo; Once the commitments are made from team members, they are <em>unconditional</em> regardless of the whirlwind and the team member is accountable to each other.</p>

<p>Finally, a successful 4DX not only helps the team to achieve the specific WIG but also produces a winning team that performs at the next level and is ready for the next WIG.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Design of Everyday Things]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.jjyao.me/blog/2022/06/21/the-design-of-everyday-things/"/>
    <updated>2022-06-21T22:40:54-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.jjyao.me/blog/2022/06/21/the-design-of-everyday-things</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What&rsquo;s a good design? How to produce a good design? This book provides some answers.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Human-centered Design</h2>

<p>A good design should be human-centered. It should put human needs, capabilities, and behavior first, then accommodate those needs, capabilities, and ways of behaving. <em>The design should adapt to people, not the opposite</em>.</p>

<p>A good design should be understandable and usable. The design should help users establish a concept model of the system that is an explanation, usually highly simplified, of how the system works. There are seven design principles to achieve a good design:</p>

<ul>
<li>Discoverability: It is possible to determine what actions are possible and the current state of the device.</li>
<li>Feedback: There is full and continuous information about the results of actions and the current state of the product or service. After an action has been executed, it is easy to determine the new state.</li>
<li>Conceptual model: The design projects all the information needed to create a good conceptual model of the system, leading to understanding and a feeling of control. The conceptual model enhances both discoverability and evaluation of results.</li>
<li>Affordances: The proper affordances exist to make the desired actions possible.</li>
<li>Signifiers: Effective use of signifiers ensures discoverability and that the feedback is well communicated and intelligible.</li>
<li>Mappings: The relationship between controls and their actions follows the principles of good mapping, enhanced as much as possible through spatial layout and temporal contiguity.</li>
<li>Constraints: Providing physical, logical, semantic, and cultural constraints guides actions and eases interpretation.</li>
</ul>


<h2>The Double-Diamond Model of Design</h2>

<p>Finding the right problem and finding the right solution are the two components of design and this corresponds to the two phases of the design process. The double-diamond model of design describes these two phases.</p>

<p><img src="/images/post/the-design-of-everyday-things/double-diamond-model-of-design.png"></p>

<p>To find the real, ROOT problem to solve, we can use the <em>five whys</em> approach. We should keep asking why until we find the real, fundamental, root problem. Don&rsquo;t rely on whatever people tell you because they will tell you that they want &ldquo;a faster horse&rdquo;. In fact, the author has a somewhat counterintuitive rule for himself: never solve the problem I am asked to solve. Because the problem being asked to solve, invariably, is not the real, fundamental, root problem.</p>

<h2>No Human Error, Only Bad Design</h2>

<p>Human error usually is a result of poor design. Whenever human errors happen, we should think about how we can design better to eliminate those errors or reduce the impact if complete elimination is impossible. This is an important mindset to have: if a system lets you make the error, it&rsquo;s badly designed.</p>

<p>There are several design practices to prevent human errors:</p>

<ul>
<li>Avoid procedures that have identical opening steps but then diverge.</li>
<li>Ensure that controls and displays for different purposes are significantly different from one another.</li>
<li>Try to avoid modes. If they are necessary, the equipment must make it obvious which mode is invoked.</li>
<li>People will be interrupted during their activities and they may need assistance in resuming their operations.</li>
<li>Don&rsquo;t count on much being retained in people&rsquo;s short-term memory. The most effective way of helping people remember is to make it unnecessary.</li>
</ul>


<h2>Successful Product, Successful Design</h2>

<p>The author argues that the design is successful only if the final product is successful —— if people buy it, use it and enjoy it. It doesn&rsquo;t matter how great the design is if people don&rsquo;t buy it.</p>

<p>To create a successful product, people should focus on strengths, not weaknesses. If the product has real strengths, it can afford to just be &ldquo;good enough&rdquo; in the other areas. People should also focus on the true needs of the people who use the product and ignore competing voices.</p>

<p>To turn a good idea into a successful product requires <em>timing</em>. Good ideas that appear too early will fail even if eventually others introduce them successfully. It takes a long time (may be decades), for good ideas to traverse the distance from conception to successful products. We should <em>ride the wave</em> to make the product more likely to be successful.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Crossing the Chasm]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.jjyao.me/blog/2021/12/27/crossing-the-chasm/"/>
    <updated>2021-12-27T20:26:25-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.jjyao.me/blog/2021/12/27/crossing-the-chasm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For B2B high-tech startup, there is a period when the product is already successful in the early market and is trying to enter the mainstream market. This period is called crossing-the-chasm period and it&rsquo;s peril. Many startups die during this period and never reach the mainstream market. This book tells us why there is such a period and why it&rsquo;s dangerous. It also shows how we can get through this period and be successful in the mainstream market.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h2>Technology Adoption Life Cycle</h2>

<p><img src="/images/post/crossing-the-chasm/technology-adoption-life-cycle.png"></p>

<p>For the technology or product offered by a company, its adoption goes through several phases from left to right.</p>

<h4>Innovators (Technology Enthusiasts)</h4>

<p>This is a group of people who are techies. They just like new technologies for its own sake and are willing to try them. They don&rsquo;t represent a significant market in themselves, nor do they have enough buying power. However they are still important to win over because 1) they are the sounding board and test bed for the new technology or product 2) they are the reference base for early adopters.</p>

<h4>Early Adopters (Visionaries)</h4>

<p>This group of people treat the new technology or product as an opportunity to have a strategic leap forward. They want fundamental breakthrough enabled by the new technology and are willing to take high risks due to the potential order-of-magnitude return on investment. These people have big budget to implement their strategic initiative so they are an important source of high-tech development capital.</p>

<h4>Early Majority (Pragmatists)</h4>

<p>These people represent the mainstream market that any startup wants to win due to its volume. Unlike visionaries, they want incremental, predictable improvements instead of disruptive ones. They have the following characteristics: 1) they are loyal once won and will even help you to defend new comers 2) they want to buy the <em>whole product</em> from the <em>market leader</em> 3) they reference other pragmatists not visionaries.</p>

<h4>Late Majority (Conservatives)</h4>

<p>They buy the extremely mature product with low cost just to stay on par with the rest of the world. They are the low-margin end of the market but have high volume.</p>

<h4>Laggards (Skeptics)</h4>

<p>Even though they may not buy products, they do point continually to the discrepancies between the sales claims and the delivered product. Startups should use their feedbacks to continuously improving the products.</p>

<h2>Word of Mouth</h2>

<p>In the high-tech buying process, word of mouth is the number-one source of information that buyers reference. People reference each other during the buying decision.</p>

<h2>Whole Product</h2>

<p><img src="/images/post/crossing-the-chasm/whole-product.png"></p>

<p>In the mainstream market, people want to buy whole product not core product. In other words, they want to buy the product that has a surrounding ecosystem, which radically reduces their burden of support. Since whole products grow up around the market leading products and not around the others, pragmatists buy from market leaders.</p>

<h2>Chasm</h2>

<p>The chasm between visionaries and pragmatists exists because visionaries is a very poor reference base for pragmatists. They are fundamentally different groups of people for the following reasons: 1) visionaries don&rsquo;t need many references to buy a product, rather they want to be the first to buy the product and create competitive advantage; pragmatists, on the other hand, need extensive reference to prove the validity of the new product 2) visionaries care more about the future, in fact, they are defining the future, while pragmatists don&rsquo;t put a lot of stake in futuristic things 3) visionaries don&rsquo;t expect the existence of the whole product and they are willing to piece together one themselves in return for getting a jump on their competition, while pragmatists only want to buy the whole product 4) visionaries, successful or not, don&rsquo;t plan to stick around long while pragmatists are cautious about their decisions since they know they will have to live with the results. This effectively means that when we try to win over pragmatists, there is effectively no reference base to start with.</p>

<h2>D-Day</h2>

<p>The way to cross the chasm successfully is by launching a D-Day type of invasion focusing on a highly specific target segment within a mainstream marketplace.</p>

<h4>Target the Point of Attack</h4>

<p>The first thing to do is finding the target niche market segment which is also called the beachhead segment. The segment should be <em>big enough to matter, small enough to win and good fit with your crown jewels</em>. Customers in that segment should have compelling reason to buy the product or in other words, feel enough pain. Instead of picking the optimal beachhead to be successful, which is very hard if not impossible, what more important is winning whatever good enough beachhead that&rsquo;s picked.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s very important to pick a very specific beachhead to conquer instead of the entire mainstream market when we are crossing the chasm for the following reasons: 1) word-of-mouth has boundaries which is ususally within a market segment so winning over one or two customers in each of five or ten different segments is worse than winning four or five customers in one segment in terms of word-of-mouth effect 2) it&rsquo;s easier to become <em>a big fish in a small pond</em> and achieve market leadership given that pragmatists want to buy from market leaders 3) our scarce resource is only enough to build the whole product for a single niche market.</p>

<h4>Assemble the Invasion Force</h4>

<p>The next thing is creating the ecosystem around our core product, namely the whole product. This often requires bringing in partners and allies needed to make it a reality.</p>

<h4>Define the Battle</h4>

<p>Then we need to create the competition and positioning in order for our product to be <em>easy to buy</em>. Viable competition is important since where there is no competition, there is no market. <em>Market alternatives</em> indicate the existence of the budget dollars to buy our products and <em>product alternatives</em> call out the differentiation. The positioning of our product should be short enough to pass the elevator test so that it can successfully create and occupy a space inside the target customers&#8217; head.</p>

<h4>Launch the Invasion</h4>

<p>Finally we need to select the intended distribution channel and set pricing to give us motivational leverage over that channel.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Multipliers: How the Best Leaders Make Everyone Smarter]]></title>
    <link href="http://blog.jjyao.me/blog/2021/08/29/multipliers-how-the-best-leaders-make-everyone-smarter/"/>
    <updated>2021-08-29T22:07:08-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://blog.jjyao.me/blog/2021/08/29/multipliers-how-the-best-leaders-make-everyone-smarter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When you ask people if they want to be multipliers who make surrounding people better or diminishers who make everyone worse, most people will say that they want to be multipliers. However, in reality, many people are accidental diminishers in some aspects. Being a true multiplier requires a multiplier mindset and certain approaches. This book tells you what multipliers are and how to become one.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Multipliers are leaders who make people better and more capable. They can access and revitalize the intelligence in the people around them. They are <em>genius makers</em> by accessing and multiplying the genius in others. They have a <em>growth mindset</em>, which is a belief that basic qualities like intelligence and ability can be cultivated through effort. In contrast, diminishers drain intelligence and capability out of the people around them.</p>

<h2>Multiplier Mindset</h2>

<p>What people believe affects their behaviors. As a result, we need to have a multiplier mindset first in order to become one. The fundamental assumption a multiplier has is that people are smart. They discover the genius in people by asking &ldquo;how is this person smart?&rdquo;. Multipliers believe that:</p>

<ol>
<li><em>People are smart and will figure things out.</em></li>
<li><em>If I can find someone&rsquo;s genius, I can put them to work.</em></li>
<li><em>People&rsquo;s best thinking must be given, not taken.</em></li>
<li><em>People get smarter by being challenged.</em></li>
<li><em>With enough minds, we can figure it out.</em></li>
</ol>


<h2>Challenger vs Know-it-all</h2>

<p>Since multipliers believe that people get smarter by being challenged, they ask really insightful and interesting questions that make people think. They don&rsquo;t limit the team to what they know, they push their teams beyond their own knowledge and that of the organization. Even if they have the answer, the don&rsquo;t just give them. Instead, they just provide enough information to provoke thinking and to help people discover and see the opportunity for themselves. <em>What&rsquo;s more important as a leader is not having the right answer but asking the right questions.</em></p>

<h2>Debate Maker vs Decision Maker</h2>

<p>Multipliers believe that with enough minds, we can figure it out. As a result, they like <em>collective debate</em>. Through debate, they challenge and stretch what people know, thus making the organization smarter over time and creating the organizational will to execute the decisions made. In contrast, when people execute an undebated decision, they turn to debating the soundness of a decision rather than executing it.</p>

<h2>Liberator vs Tyrant</h2>

<p>Multipliers believe that people&rsquo;s best thinking must be given, not taken. They provide a safe environment for people to think and make mistakes. The highest quality of thinking cannot emerge without learning and learning can&rsquo;t happen without mistakes. <em>Intimidation and fear rarely produce truly great work.</em> Speaking of creating a safe environment, there is no easier way to invite experimentation and learning than to <em>share stories about multipliers&#8217; own mistakes</em>.</p>

<p>While multiplier gives space and safe environment, they also demand the best work. It&rsquo;s a fair trade. They create an intense environment that requires people&rsquo;s best thinking and their best work. They generate pressue, but they don&rsquo;t generate stress. Requiring people&rsquo;s best work is different from insisting on desired outcomes. Stress is created when people are expected to produce outcomes that are beyond their control. But they feel positive pressure when they are held to their best work. <em>Multipliers distinguish best work from outcomes.</em></p>

<h2>Investor vs Micro-manager</h2>

<p>Multipliers believe that people are smart and will figure things out. So they operate as investors, giving ownership that keeps rolling back to other people. As investors, they define ownership, invest resources and hold people <em>accountable</em>. When they teach, they invest in their people&rsquo;s ability to solve and avoid problems in the future. In the end, multipliers enable others to operate independently by giving other people ownership for results and investing in their success. They create organizations that can perform and win, not only without them on the field, but long after their direct influence is felt.</p>

<h2>Talent Magnet vs Empire Builder</h2>

<p>Multipliers believe that if I can find someone&rsquo;s genius, I can put them to work. They are like magnets that draw in talent and develop it to its fullset. They look for talent everywhere, find people&rsquo;s <em>native genius</em>, utilize people at their fullsets and remove the blockers. Multipliers not only notice people&rsquo;s talent, they <em>label</em> it for them. By telling people what they see, they raise people&rsquo;s awareness and confidence, allowing them to provide their capability more fully. What&rsquo;s more, once they uncover the native genius of others, they look for opportunities that demand that capability.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
